tripwire.com 2019-12-31

# Tripwire Privacy Policy

_Privacy Notice Updated May 2018_

Tripwire respects your right to privacy. This Privacy Notice explains who we are, how we collect, share and use personal information about you, and how you can exercise your privacy rights. This Privacy Notice only applies to personal information that we collect through our website at www.tripwire.com (“ **Website** ”). 

If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your personal information, please contact us using the contact details provided at the bottom of this Privacy Notice.

###### Quick links

We recommend that you read this Privacy Notice in full to ensure you are fully informed. However, if you only want to access a particular section of this Privacy Notice, then you can click on the relevant link below to jump to that section.

  * What personal information does Tripwire collect and why?
  * Who does Tripwire share my information with?
  * Legal basis for processing personal information
  * Cookies and similar tracking technology
  * How does Tripwire keep my personal information secure?
  * International data transfers
  * Data retention
  * Your data protection rights
  * Modifications to Our privacy notice

###### What does Tripwire do?

Tripwire is a leading provider of integrity assurance solutions that drive security, compliance and operational excellence. As the inventor of file integrity monitoring (FIM), Tripwire has a 20-year history of innovation. Today, Tripwire helps organizations, including half of the Fortune 500, achieve visibility across their networks, reduce their attack surfaces, and stay on top of suspicious changes – steps considered foundational to system and data integrity. Tripwire’s award-winning portfolio includes configuration management, file integrity management, asset discovery, vulnerability management and log collection.

For more information about Tripwire, please see the About Us section of our Website at <https://www.tripwire.com/company/>.

###### What personal information does Tripwire collect and why?

The personal information that we may collect about you broadly falls into the following categories:

  * _Information that you provide voluntarily_

Certain parts of our Website may ask you to provide personal information voluntarily: for example, we may ask you to provide your contact details when you register to download free evaluation software, fill out a survey, send us an email, or when you request pricing, marketing collateral or Tripwire services. Depending on the circumstances, we may collect personal information, volunteered by you, such as your name, job title, company name and contact information (work phone, email, fax, address and email address). We may use the information to help you complete a transaction, update you on services, or manage your account registration. We may also share your information with Tripwire affiliates to provide you with additional service opportunities. The personal information that you are asked to provide, and the reasons why you are asked to provide it, will be made clear to you at the point we ask for your personal information.

  * _Information that we collect automatically_

When you visit our Website, we may collect certain information automatically from your device. In some countries, including countries in the European Economic Area, this information may be considered personal information under applicable data protection laws.

Specifically, the information we collect automatically may include information like anonymous session-specific information that is passively collected when you visit our Website, your IP address,, browser type or domain name, the web pages and search terms you use for our Website only, and the date and time of your visit. We use the information to better understand your needs, improve the contents of our web pages and to ensure technical performance of our network.

Collecting this information enables us to better understand the visitors who come to our Website, where they come from, and what content on our Website is of interest to them. We use this information for our internal analytics purposes and to improve the quality and relevance of our Website for our visitors.

Some of this information may be collected using cookies and similar tracking technology, as explained further under the heading “Cookies and similar tracking technology” below.

  * _Information that we obtain from third party sources_

From time to time, we may receive personal information about you from third party sources, but only where we have checked that these third parties either have your consent or are otherwise legally permitted or required to disclose your personal information to us.

The type of information we collect from third parties includes name and email addresses; we use the information we receive from these third parties to maintain and improve the accuracy of the records we hold about you.

In general, we will use the personal information we collect from you only for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice or for purposes that we explain to you at the time we collect your personal information. However, we may also use your personal information for other purposes that are not incompatible with the purposes we have disclosed to you (such as archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes, or statistical purposes) if and where this is permitted by applicable data protection laws.

###### Who does Tripwire share my personal information with?

We may disclose your personal information to the following categories of recipients:

  * to our **group companies, third party services providers and partners** who provide data processing services to us (for example, to support the delivery of, provide functionality on, or help to enhance the security of our Website), or who otherwise process personal information for purposes that are described in this Privacy Notice or are notified to you when we collect your personal information. A list of our current group companies is available in Belden Inc.’s most recent annual report on Form 10-K, filed with the United States Securities and Exchange Commission and available at <http://investor.belden.com/investor-relations>.
  * to any **competent law enforcement body, regulatory, government agency, court or other third party** where we believe disclosure is necessary (i) as a matter of applicable law or regulation, (ii) to exercise, establish or defend our legal rights, or (iii) to protect your vital interests or those of any other person;
  * to a **potential buyer** (and its agents and advisers) in connection with any proposed purchase, merger or acquisition of any part of our business, provided that we inform the buyer it must use your personal information only for the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Notice;
  * to any **other person with your consent** to the disclosure.

###### Legal basis for processing personal information

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contact with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information).

Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us using the contact details provided under the "How to contact us” heading below.

###### Cookies and similar tracking technology

We use cookies and similar tracking technology (collectively, “Cookies”) to collect and use personal information about you. For further information about the types of Cookies we use, why, and how you can control Cookies, please see our Cookie Notice.

###### How does Tripwire keep my personal information secure?

We use appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect the personal information that we collect and process about you. The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal information.

We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete and current and we use industry standard encryption technology when transferring and receiving client information exchanged with our Website.

All personal information gathered on the Website and stored by Tripwire is maintained in secure facilities that limit access to authorized personnel only. We regularly test our Website for security breaches to reduce the risk of unauthorized viewing.

###### International data transfers

Your personal information may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country.

Specifically, our Website servers are located in the US, and our group companies and third party service providers and partners operate around the world. This means that when we collect your personal information we may process it in any of these countries.

However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Notice. These include certification under Privacy Shield and implementing the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of personal information between our group companies, which require all group companies to protect personal information they process from the EEA in accordance with European Union data protection law. Additionally, we are in the processing of applying for Binding Corporate Rules.

###### Data retention

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements).

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

###### Your data protection rights

Under applicable data protection laws, you may have the following data protection rights:

  * If you wish to **access, correct, update or request deletion** of your personal information, you can do so at any time by contacting us using the contact details provided under the  heading below.
  * In addition, you can **object to processing** of your personal information, ask us to **restrict processing** of your personal information or **request portability** of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us using the contact details provided under the  heading below.
  * You have the right to **opt-out of marketing communications** we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing e-mails we send you. To opt-out of other forms of marketing (such as postal marketing or telemarketing), please contact us using the contact details provided under the  heading below.
  * If we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can **withdraw your consent** at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * You have the **right to complain to a data protection authority** about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

###### How often does Tripwire change its Privacy Notice?

We may update this Privacy Notice from time to time in response to changing legal, technical or business developments. When we update our Privacy Notice, we will take appropriate measures to inform you, consistent with the significance of the changes we make. We will obtain your consent to any material Privacy Notice changes if and where this is required by applicable data protection laws.

You can see when this Privacy Notice was last updated by checking the “last updated” date displayed at the top of this Privacy Notice.

###### What else should I know about Tripwire's Privacy Notice?

Tripwire does not publish text, images, or multimedia content that portray nudity, foul language, violence or other information not suitable for children. Websites maintained by Tripwire are not directed to children under the age of 13. Tripwire will not knowingly collect or maintain personal information from or about anyone under 13.

###### Additional Privacy Questions?

If you have any further questions or concerns about Tripwire's Privacy Notice, please contact us at [privacy@tripwire.com](mailto:privacy@tripwire.com) with the subject line heading of “Privacy Notice.” You can also call us at [503.276.7500](tel:+15032767500) or send mail directed to:

Tripwire Inc.  
ATTN: Legal Department  
308 SW Second Ave, Suite 400  
Portland, OR 97204  
U.S.A.

###### Tripwire Contact

This is the Website for Tripwire, Inc. Our postal address is:

Tripwire Headquarters  
308 SW Second Ave, Suite 400  
Portland, OR 97204

We can be reached via e-mail at [webmaster@tripwire.com](mailto:webmaster@tripwire.com) or you can reach us by telephone at [503.276.7500](tel:+15032767500).
